I was asked by Wilsonart International,
لقد دعيت من قبل ويلسونارت الدولية
a plastic laminate company, which is
شركة للألواح البلاستيكية
the largest plastic laminate company in the world --
وهي أكبر شركة للألواح البلاستيكية في العالم
they asked me to design
طلبوا مني تصميم
a trade show booth
كشك لهم
for exhibition at the International Contemporary Furniture Fair
ليعرض في معرض الأثاث الدولي المعاصر
in New York, in 2000.
في نيويورك 2000
So looking at their three main markets
وبالنظر إلى أسواقهم الثلاثة الرئيسية
for their product which were basically
لمنتجاتهم والذين كانوا في الأساس
transportation design,
مصممي النقل
interiors and furniture,
والديكور والأثاث
we came up with the solution of taking
جئنا بفكرة أخذ
an old Airstream trailer and gutting it,
مقطورة إير ستريمر قديمة
and trying to portray laminate,
ومحاولة تصوير الغلاف البلاستيكي
and a trailer, in kind of a
ومقطورة، بطريقة
fresh, new contemporary look.
منعشة، بنظرة معاصر جديدة
When this trailer showed up at my shop
حين ظهرت هذه المقطورة في ورشتي
in Berkeley, I'd actually never stepped foot in
في بيركلي، لم تطأ قدمي في
an Airstream trailer, or any other trailer.
مقطورة إير ستريمر، أو أي مقطورة أخرى
So I can be somebody that can look at this
لذا فقد كنت شخصا يمكنه النظر إلى هذا
in a totally fresh perspective and see if I can
بطريقة جديدة تماما لأبحث إذا كنت أستطيع
optimize it in its most idealistic fashion.
استخدامها بالطريقة المثلى
I decided I had to do some research
وقررت أنني أحتاج إلى إجراء بعض البحث
and really figure out what had gone wrong
وأكتشف ما الخطأ الذي حدث
somewhere along the history of Airstream.
في مكان ما في تاريخ الإير ستريمر
What I discovered in these interiors is that
والذي اكتشفته في هذه الديكورات هو أن
there was a disconnect between the exterior shell
هناك انفصام بين الهيكل الخارجي
and the interior architecture of the pieces.
والتصميم الداخلي للقطعة
In that the shell was originally conceived
بأن الهيكل صمم في الأصل
as a lightweight, modern, futuristic,
ككبسولة تقنية خفيفة
high-tech pod for hurtling down the freeway, and
حديثة ومستقبلية للركض بها في الخط السريع
the interiors were completely out of sync with that.
والداخل كان غير متناغم تماما مع ذلك
In fact it appeared like they
في الواقع فقد بدا كأنهم
referenced a mountain cabin.
نسخوا كبينة جبلية
That seemed really like a crisis to me,
وقد بدا ذلك لي كأزمة
that they had never been able to
بأنهم لم يتمكنوا أبدا من
develop a vocabulary
تكوين مفردات
about escape, and about travel, and modernity
عن الهرب، وعن السفر، والحداثة
in this trailer that was consistent with the shell.
في هذه المقطورة، والمتوافقة مع الهيكل
We really needed to do some archeology
نحتاج فعلا للتنقيب
in the trailer itself to figure out what's authentic
داخل المقطورة ذاتها، لنكتشف ما هو الأصلي
in an Airstream trailer,
في مقطورة الإير ستريمر
and what feels like it has true purpose and utility.
وما الذي لهو هدف حقيقي وفائدة
We stripped out all the vinyl
جردناها من جميع الفينيل
and zolatone paint that was covering up
والطلاء الذي كان يغطيها
this just fantastic aluminum shell.
هذا الهيكل الألمونيوم الرائع
We took off all the visible hardware and trim
اقتلعنا جميع الأجهزة الظاهرة وقلمنا
that was kind of doing the country cabin thing.
كل ما كان يعطي انطباع الكبينة
I literally drew on the walls of the trailer,
لقد قمت حرفيا بالرسم على جدران المقطورة
mocked it up in cardboard,
نسختها على ورق مقوى
we'd come in and cut, decide things were wrong,
كنا ندخل ونقطع، نقرر أن أمر ما خاطئ
pull it out, put it back in.
نخرجه، نعيده
The main goal was to smooth out the interior,
الهدف الرئيسي كان لجعل الداخل أكثر سلاسة
and begin to speak about motion,
ويبدأ في التحدث عن الحركة
and mobility, and independence.
التنقل والاستقلالية
The biggest difficulty on one of these trailers
أن أصعب ما في هذه المقطورات
is that when you're designing there's actually no
أنه حين تصمم لا يوجد في الواقع
logical place to stop and start materials
مكان منطقي لبدء أو إنهاء الخامات
because of the continuous form of the trailer.
بسبب الشكل المتصل للمقطورة
There's no such things as two walls and a ceiling
فيلا يوجد جدارين وسقف
coming together, where you can change materials and shapes.
يلتقون، حيث يمكنك تغير الخامات والأشكال
So that became a challenge.
فأصبح ذلك تحد
Compounding that,
أضف إلى ذلك
the material of choice, laminate,
المادة المنتقاة، ألواح البلاستك
that I was trying to highlight,
والمفترض أن أظهرها
only bends in two dimensions.
يطعج فقط باتجاهين
It's a compound curve interior.
إنها غرفة منحنية
What I had to devise was
كان علي ابتكار
a way of fooling the eye
طريقة لخداع العين
into believing that all these panels
لتصدق أن كل هذه الألواح
are curved with the shell.
منحنية مع الهيكل
What I came up with was
والذي توصلت إليه كان
a series of second skins
سلسلة من الجلود الثانوية
that basically float over the aluminum shell.
والتي تطفو مبدئيا على الهيكل الألمونيوم
And what I was trying to do there was
والذي كنت أحاول فعله هناك
direct your eye in the space,
هو توجيه عينك في المساحة
so that you would perceive the geometry in a different way,
لتهيئ لك الأبعاد بطريقة مختلفة
and that the casework wouldn't break up the space.
وأن الأثاث لن يفتت المساحة
They also gave us a way to run power
كما أنها أعطتنا طريقة لمد الأسلاك
and rewire the trailer without tearing out the skin,
وإعادة تسليك المقطورة دون تمزيق الغطاء
so they function as an electrical chase.
فهي تعمل كعلب كهربائية
That's the trailer, pretty much finished.
هذه المقطورة، شبه منتهية
That trailer led to another commission,
هذه المقطورة قادتنا إلى مشروع آخر
to participate in whats called Tokyo Designers Block.
للمشاركة في ما يسمى حي المصممين في طوكيو
Its a week of furniture design events in Tokyo, in October.
إنه حدث لمدة أسبوع في طوكيو في أكتوبر
Teruo Kurosaki, who owns a furniture company called Idee,
تيرو كوروساكي، الذي يملك شركة تدعى إديي
he asked me to ship him two trailers to Tokyo.
طلب مني إرسال مقطورتين إلى طوكيو
He said one he would like to
أحدهما يود أن
make a real trailer, functioning, and we would sell that one.
يجعلها مقطورة حقيقية، عملية، وسنبيعها
Trailer number two, you have a blank slate, you can to anything you want.
المقطورة الثانية، لديكم صفحة بيضاء، يمكنكم فعل ما تريدونه
We came up with a fantasy scenario
خرجنا بموقف خيالي
of a DJ traveling around the States,
لدي جي يسافر حول الولايات
that would collect records and go on tours.
يجمع الاسطوانات ويتبع الحفلات
This trailer housed two turntables,
بداخل هذه المقطورة طاولتين
mixer, wet bar, fridge, integrated sound system.
بار، ثلاجة، ونظام صوتي
It's got a huge couch, fits quite a few people,
بها أريكة ضخمة، تسع لعدد جيد من الناس
and basically we'd had a great time with this.
وقد استمتعنا بوقتنا في هذه
And so in this trailer I took it upon myself to think about travel,
لذا ففي هذه المقطورة أخذت على عاتقي التفكير في السفر
and escape, in an idiosyncratic sense.
والهرب، بحس صاعد
A lot of these ideas migrated into
كثير من هذه الأفكار وصلت إلى
the production trailers for Airstream.
إنتاج مقطورات الإير ستريمر
This brings us up to the time that I started consulting to Airstream.
هذا يوصلنا إلى حين بدئت بتقديم المشورات لإير ستريمر
They came to me and said,
جاءوني وقالوا
"Well, what can we do to freshen this thing up?
حسنا، ما الذي يمكننا فعله لنجدد هذا الشيء
And do you think kids, you know, skateboarders, surfers,
وهل تعتقد أن الشباب، كما تعلم، المتزلجين على الطرقات والأمواج
rock climbers, would use these things?"
متسلقي الجبال، سيستخدمون هذه الأشياء
And I said, "Well, not in that interior."
فقلت "ليس بهذا الديكور"ـ
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Anyway, I went out to Airstream
عموما، ذهبت إلى إير ستريمر
about six times during the process of building this prototype,
حوالي ست مرات خلال عملية بناء هذا النموذج
and it's called the Bambi prototype.
ويدعى نموذج بامبي
I thought, "Finally, oh yeah great,
فكرت "إخيرا، عظيم
big company, I'm gonna work with somebody with money
شركة كبيرة، سأعمل مع شخص لديه أموال
for tooling and molding."
للأدوات والقوالب"ـ
And I walked in their prototype facility, and
ودخلت مقر النماذج لديهم
it's exactly like my shop, only bigger --
وهو تماما كورشتي، ولكنه أكبر
same tools, same things.
نفس الأدوات، نفس الأشياء
So the problem became -- and they set this dilemma to me --
فأصبحت المشكلة، وقد وضعوا هذه المعضلة لي
that you have to design the interior using only our existing technology,
عليك أن تصمم الداخل باستخدام تقنياتنا الحالية فقط
and there's no money for tooling or molding.
ولا توجد ميزانية للأدوات أو القوالب
The trailers themselves are actually hand-built.
المقطورات نفسها مصنوعة يدويا
All the casework is hand-scribed in, uniquely,
كل الأثاث تثبت يدويا
so you can't just cut 100 parts for 100 trailers,
فلا نستطيع قص 100 قطعة لـ 100 مقطورة
you have to cut them big, and every single one is hand-fit.
عليك قصها كبيرة، وكل واحدة تثبت يدويا
They didn't want to go to a componentized system.
لم يريدوا التحول إلى نظام عنصري
And there it is, that's the Bambi 16.
وها هي ذي، بامبي 16
(Applause)
(تصفيق)